ANIRUDH SHIDGANESH

<u>Name</u> : Anirudh Shastri Shidganesh

Qualifications : Qualified M.A. in Psychology in 2015.

: Qualified MH-SET held in May-2016

: Qualified UGC-NET with JRF held in July-2016

<u>Languages</u> : Marathi, Hindi, English

<u>**Age**</u> : 30 years



About me - I am hardworking and disciplined. I am interested in learning and sharing knowledge

that can be helpful to understand the human behavior. Currently, I am exploring some aspects of human behavior through research. I believe my communication skills and

experiences can be best utilized through teaching in educational organization.

Academic Background

Year Qualification

2015 M.A. in Psychology from Savitribai Phule Pune University with First Class Distinction.

Diploma in Yogshikshak from YCMOU, Nashik with First Class Distinction.

2013 B.Sc. (Zoology) from University of Pune with First Class Distinction.

2010 H.S.C. from MSBSHSE with First class. 2008 S.S.C. from MSBSHSE with first class.

Professional Experience

<u>Duration</u> <u>Designation</u> <u>Organisation</u>

2017-Present (5 years 0 days) Senior research fellow Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee 2017-21 (5 Semesters) Teaching Assistant Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee

2015-17 (1 year 7 months) Psychologist Manasnaad Psychological Health Center, Nashik

2016-17 (5 months 30 days) Health Care Volunteer Moksh De-addiction and Rehabilitation Center, Nashik

2015-16 (9 months 14 days) Counselor Darshan Academy, Devlali

Other Qualifications

NCC 'B' Cert National Cadet Corps, 7 Maharashtra Battalion

2012-13 NCC 'C' Cert National Cadet Corps, 7 Maharashtra Battalion

2013-14 Diploma in Yoga Teacher Ashirwad Yog-Naturopathy College, Nashik (YCMOU)

2015 (7 Days) Certificate Course in Counselling Institute for Human relations, Counselling and

Psychotherapy, CCC Vellore.

Contact no. : +91 8446586850

E-mail ID : anirudhshidganesh@gmail.com

Correspondence address : Room no. 202, Radha Krishnan Bhawan, Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee,

Uttarakhand – 247667.

ANIRUDH SHIDGANESH

Conference Paper Presented

- Shidganesh, A., & Singh, R. M. (2019). Military to Civilian Transition: An Overview. In WARMCAMP 2019: International Conference on Military Psychology and Counseling (pp. 1-30). Mumbai, India.
- Shidganesh, A. & Singh, R. M. (2020). Development and establishment of psychometric properties of Scale to Measure Perceived Changes during Military to Civilian Transition. In WARMCAMP 2020: International conference on Military Psychology and Counseling. Pune, India.

Faculty Development Programs

- "Data Analysis using SPSS" organised by Mahatma Gandhi University in association with AICTE Training and Learning Academy Online FDP, from 5th October 2020 to 9th October 2020.
- "Structural Equation Modelling" organised by Manipal Institute of Management in association with AICTE Training and Learning Academy Online FDP, from 17th May 2020 to 21st May 2021.
- "Data Science with Statistical Methods using R" organised by Amity University, Lucknow, U.P. in association with AICTE Training and Learning Academy Online FDP, from 21st 25th June 2021.
- "Analysis of Categorical Data" organised online by International Management Institute, Bhubaneswar in association with AICTE Training and Learning Academy Online FDP, from 8th 12th November 2021.
- "Advanced Research Methodology Qualitative Data & Open source tools" organised online by Government of Maharashtra Sydenham Institute of Management, Mumbai in association with AICTE Training and Learning Academy Online FDP, from 21st 25th February 2022.

Workshops

- "A short term Course Module on Qualitative Research Methods" organized by Department of Architecture and Planning, IIT Roorkee from 07th March 2019 to 28th March 2019.
- "Write a Publication ready manuscript and get closer to acceptance." by Wiley Publications in association with MGCL, IIT Roorkee on 1st June 2019.
- "Training Session on Web of Science, Endnote & Incites" workshop organized by Clarivate Analytics in association with MGCL, IIT Roorkee on 7th September 2019
- "Mapping your Dissertation: A Training Workshop on Writing Thesis & Dissertation" by SAGE Publicatios in association with MGCL. IIT Roorkee on 7th December 2019.
- "Introduction to Content Analysis with WordStat" organized by Provalis Research in conjunction with the University of West Indies and the Mixed Methods International Research Association Caribbean Chapter on 26th February 2021 from 10:30 PM to 12:30 AM IST.

ANIRUDH SHIDGANESH

Webinars

- "How to publish open access with Taylor & Francis" organized by Taylor & Francis on Tuesday, 28th April 2020 12:30 PM 1:30 PM IST.
- "Publishing with F1000Research" organized by Taylor & Francis Review on Tuesday, 12th May 2020 12:30 PM -10:30 PM IST.

"Open-Source tools for data analysis in Social Sciences." Organized by Department of Commerce, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal on Friday, 31st July 2020 6:00 PM to 7:30 PM IST. "Military and Veteran Spouses' Challenges - Unmet Needs and Extent of Available Support Programs" organized by Graduate School of Professional Psychology, University of Denver, U.S.A. on Saturday, 27th February 2021 from 12:30 a.m.- 1:30 a.m. IST. "Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Substance Use Disorders (CBT-SUD)" organized by Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention, VA Central Office, U.S.A. on Saturday, 25th March 2021 from 11:30 p.m. - 12:30 a.m. IST. The Curriculum Vitae is up-to-date as on - 17th May 2022